Guide to the Wallace Earle Stegner Creative Writing Program: correspondence and manuscripts, 1949-1992
Department of Special Collections
Wallace Earle Stegner Creative Writing Program: correspondence and manuscripts,
1949-1992
Special Collections M0558
Stegner, Wallace Earle, 1909-
3.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Wallace Stegner, 1987, 1989, 1990, 1991, and his estate, 1995.
Biographical Note
American author. Head of the Creative Writing Program at Stanford for many years. The Creative Writing Center was founded in 1946 and was the second degree granting program (after Iowa) in the country.
Scope and Content
Primarily incoming correspondence and some outgoing. Includes literary manuscripts by Pauline Bates Alden, Frank Bergon, Neilma Gantner, Mary Jane Moffat, Jack Nisbet, and Nancy Packer.
Access Terms
Abbey, Edward, 1927-; Alden, Paulette Bates, 1947-; Allan, Donald A.; Aranicki, Aleksandar.; Arnold, Maxwell.; Arnold, Rich.; Beresford, Thomas Patrick.; Bergon, Frank.; Bontly, Thomas, 1939-; Burdick, Eugene.; Cadle, Dean.; Canzomeri, Robert.; Crawford, Max.; Daneshvar, Simin, 1921-; Daniel, John, 1948-; Decker, William B.; Doerr, Harriet.; Doulis, Thomas.; Ferguson, Jim.; Ferguson, Suzanne, 1939-; Fuller, Blair.; Gangemi, Kenneth, 1937-; Gee, E. Gordon (Elwood Gordon), 1944-; Gerber, Joan.; Green, Hannah Wesley.; Harrison, Jeffrey.; Havazelet, Ehud.; Heintze, Carl.; Hentzell, Shirley Weinland.; Hill, Evan.; Hollister, Michael.; Houston, James, 1921-; Jones, Leonard L.; Karagiorga, Olympia.; Keithley, George, 1935-; Kiley, Norman.; Kittredge, William.; Laurence, Oliver.; Lelchuk, Alan.; L'Heureux, John.; Lynch, John.; MacDonald, David, 1945-; McLeod, Mark.; Mayer, Tom.; Merritt, Miriam.; Milani, Farzaneh Malek-Zadeh.; Moffat, Mary Jane.; Momaday, N. Scott, 1934-; Moser, Don.; Muhein, Harry Miles.; Nisbet, Jack.; Oliphant, Bob.; Packer, Nancy Huddleston.; Payne, Ladell.; Pennybacker, Mindy Eunsoo.; Pflug, Raymond J.; Popham, Melinda Worth.; Ransom, John B.; Rawlins, Chip.; Russell, T.M. (Thaddeus Mack), 1875-1958.; Ryan, Michael S.; Schaepman, Paul.; Schermerhorn, James.; Schubnell, Mathias, 1953-; Segrè, Claudio.; Spiro, Merrill.; Stanford, Donald E, 1913-; Steim, Dona.; Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968.; Stewart, John.; Strucinski, Mitchell J.; Tanzer, Ward.; Terry, Marshall, 1931-; Tomlinson, Norma.; Walker, Dave, 1905-; Wendt, Allan[?].; Wesley, John.; West, Anne.; White, Robin.; Winkes, Ken.; Worthen, Helena K.; Young, Al.; Zousmer, Steve.; Stanford University Creative Writing Program.; American literature--20th century.; Authors, American--20th century.
Container List
- Series I: Letters to and from Stegner, with other contents of envelopes: resumes, publicity blurbs, clippings, and short pieces.
  - ABBEY, Edward, 1927-: 2 items, 1972-1977.With a letter from American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters to Stegner re. Abbey, Sept. 8. 1983. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ABRAMSON, []: 1 letter of recommendation by Stegner, 1956.
  - ALDEN, Paulette Bates. 1947-: 9 items, 1970-1991.With 2 letters from Greywolf Press to Stegner re: Alden and 1 article by Alden. See also Series II.
  - ALLAN, Donald A.: 13 items (with 1 copy), 1948-1990.
  - ANDERSON, Bettylu LaVinn: 1 item, 1988. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ARANICKI, Aleksander: 1 item, 1989.
  - ARNOLD, Maxwell Jr. (Bud): 12 items, 1948-1992.With 2 letters of recommendation by Stegner and one letter from Fred Graeser re. Arnold.
  - ARNOLD, Rich: 6 items, 1948-49.
  - AYRES, Deirdre Jones: 1 item, 1972.
  - BALL, Jane Eklund: 1 item, 1990.With 1 Memorial Service Announcement (1992)and with 1 letter of recommendation from Stegner, 1954.
  - BARNETT, Hoyt: 1 item, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - BATES, Paulette: See ALDEN, Paulette Bates.
  - BAUMBACH, Jonathan: 2 items, 1963.
  - BERESFORD, Thomas Patrick: 1 item, 1986.With 2 short stories by Beresford; 1 letter by Stegner re: Beresford.
  - BERGON, Frank: 7 items, 1977-1989.With resume and grant proposal. See also Series II.
  - BERRY, Elizabeth: 1 item, 1990.
  - BERRY, Wendell, 1934-: 12 items, 1962-1984.With 1 response from Stegner, 1987.See also Series II.
  - BEYER, Jean: 1 item and 1 letter from Foreground re. Beyer, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - BONTLY, Thomas, 1939-: 27 items, 1967-90.With photocopy of The Blue Smile by Thomas Bontly.
  - BOWEN, David: 1 item, 1986. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - BOYD, Blanche M., 1945-: 1 item, 1977.
  - BOYD, Susan Kuehn: 7 items, 1972-88.
  - BRACHER, Fred: 1 letter from Stegner re. Helen Prentice and Larry Lawrence, 1956.
  - BRENEMAN, Steven Bret, 1943-: 1 item, 1980.
  - BURDICK, Eugene A.[Bud] (Eugene Allan), 1912-: 9 items, 1947-1953.With reply from Stegner, 1949;newspaper clippings re: Burdick at Oxford. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BURNS, Rex [Tom Selher, pseudonym]: 3 items, 1975- 1990.
  - BURT, Nathaniel, 1913-: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1954.
  - CADLE, Dean: 4 items, 1973,and 1 letter from Philip E. Cranston re. Cadle, 1973.
  - CAMPBELL, Sheldon: 1 item, 1978. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CANZONERI, Robert: 1 item, n.d.,1 item, 1973.With 2 letters from Donald E. Stanford.
  - CASSILL, R.V. (Ronald Verlin), 1919-: 1 item, 1968.
  - CHAMPION, Hale: 1 letter of recommendation from Stegner, 1955.
  - CHANEY, Bev: 3 items, 1991.With 1 response from Stegner, 1991.
  - CHOWDER, Ken [Glantz, Ken]: 18 items, 1980-1990.With 1 letter to Stegner re: Delicate Geometry, 1982.See Series II. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CLARK, Walter Van Tilburg, 1909-1971:2 letters from J. Paul Leonard re. Clark, 1955-1956,and 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1955.
  - CONAWAY, James: 6 items, 1970-1987.
  - CONNELL, Evan S., 1924-: 1 item, n.d.
  - COOK, Marshall J., 1944-: 1 item, 1990.
  - CRAWFORD, Constance, 1930-: 6 items, 1972-1990. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - CRAWFORD, Max, 1938-: 3 items, 1985;3 items, n.d.
  - CROSBY, Harry H.: 1 item, 1992.With newsclippings.
  - DAHL, []: 1 letter of recommendation from Stegner, 1956.
  - DANESHVAR, Simin, 1921-: 8 items, 1963-1983.With 4 items from Farzenah MILANI to Stegner re. Daneshvar; article on Daneshvar by Milani.
  - DANIEL, John, 1948-: 27 items, 1983-1992.With letter to Stegner from publisher re. Daniel. See Series II. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - DAVIE, Donald: 2 items, 1972and 1977.See also Series II. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - DAVIS, Linda: 1 item, 1966.
  - DAWKINS, Mary Lucile: 1 item, 1966.
  - DECKER, William B.: 11 items, 1973-1989.
  - DeEDS, Joanne: 3 items, 1971, 1985.
  - DeVOTO, Bernard Augustine, 1897-1955:6 items, 1944-1948.With 4 letters from Stegner. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - DIXON, Stephen, 1936-: 5 items, 1978-1981.
  - DOERR, Harriet: 3 items, 1984-88.
  - DOULIS, Thomas: 3 items, 1986-87.
  - DOUST, Dudley: 1 telegram from Time, Inc. re. Doust, 1946,and 1 recommendation from Stegner.
  - ENGLISH, Michael: 1 item, 1968. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - FANG, Liewche Tu: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1954.
  - FERGUSON, Jim: See Ferguson, Suzanne.
  - FERGUSON, Suzanne: 3 items, 1982-1988.
  - FERRONE, John: 3 items, 1962-1966.
  - FLOREN, Lee [Long, Grace]: 1 item, 1968.
  - FRANKS, Ann Russell: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1955.
  - FULLER, Blair: 4 items, 1960-1988.With letter from publisher to Stegner re. Fuller.
  - GAINES, Ernest J., 1933-: 1 letter to Stegner re. Gaines from MacArthur Foundation with attached bibliography.
  - GANGEMI, Kenneth, 1937-: 7 items, 1973-1991.With Xerox copy of Gangemi's book cover; Classroon Observation Report, 1991.See also Series II. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - GANTNER, Neilma: 18 items, 1973-1992.See Series II. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - GEE, E. GORDON: 1 item, 1988. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - GEIST, Ruth: 1 letter from Stegner, 1954.
  - GERBER, Merrill Joan: 8 items, 1972-1992.With newsclippings.
  - GIBBONS, Eileen: 1 letter from Carlton Culmsee re. Gibbons and 1 response from Stegner, 1954.
  - GILLIAM, Hal: 3 items, 1990-1991.
  - GLANTZ, Ken: See Chowder, Ken.
  - GLAZE, Andrew: 4 items, 1946.
  - GLEASON, Venetia T.: 1 item, n.d.See also Series II. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - GONZALEZ, N.V.M., 1915-: 7 items, 1955-1970.
  - GREEN, Hannah: 10 items, n.d.
  - GREEN, Hannah: 13 items, 1967-1991.With 1 letter of recommendation from Stegner, 1955. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - GRIFFITH, Beatrice: 1 item, c1954.With 1response and 1 recommendation from Stegner, both 1954.
  - GROSSER, Morton: 1 item, 1967. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - HALBERT, Sara F.: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1955.
  - HANKINS, Joanne DeEds: 2 items, 1985.
  - HARRISON, Jeffery: 1 item, 1988.
  - HAVAZELET, Ehud: 1 item, 1988.
  - HEINTZE, Carl: 17 items, 1970-1991.See also Series II. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - HELLE, Alfy: 1 item, 1956. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - HENTZELL, Shirley W.: 4 items, 1973-1992.
  - HILL, Evan: 3 items, 1992-1989.
  - HILLIS, Rick, 1956-: 2 items, 1990.
  - HOAGLAND, Edward: 1 item, 1966.
  - HOBBS, WHIT: 1 item, 1990.
  - HOLLISTER, Michael: 2 items, 1982-1989.With synopsis of Snake River; Compilation of Quotations from Meredoth; copy of letter to Hollister from John L'Heureux re. Snake River.
  - HORGAN, David: 3 items, 1982-1992.See Series II.
  - HORN, Tom: 1 item, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - HOUGH, Bud: 1 item, 1970.
  - HOULE, Constance: See Crawford, Constance.
  - HOUSE, Kay: 9 items, 1968-1973.With attached newsclipping.
  - HOUSTON, James H.: 6 items, 1963-1990.See also Series II.
  - HOWE, Fanny: 1 item, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - HUNT, Mary Fassett: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1955.
  - HUTCHINSON, James: 1 item, n.d.
  - ILYIN, Boris: 9 items, 1968-1971, 1986.
  - JAMISON, Stephen: 1 item, n.d.
  - JENKINS, Starr, 1925-: 1 item, 1990.
  - JOHNSON, Deirdre Jones: 2 items, 1983.
  - JONES, Arden: 1 item, 1971
  - JONES, Franklin: 1 item, 1965. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - JONES, Leonard L.: 1 item, 1990.
  - KARAGEORGES, Olympia: 2 items, 1967-1971.
  - KEITHLEY, George, 1935-: 2 items, 1972-1977.
  - KERR, Baine, 1946-: 1 item, 1978.
  - KILE (Kiley?), Norman: 1 item, 1983.
  - KIRBY-SMITH, Noel and Tom: 2 items, 1972-1973.
  - KITTREDGE, William: 5 items, 1978-1991.With Centennial Book Project listing.
  - KLASSEN, Joanna: See Thompson, Joanna.
  - KOHLER, Mary: 1 item, n.d.With 1 response from Stegner, 1954.
  - KRAUS, Richard: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1955.
  - LAMME, Guy Hugh:: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1955. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - LAWRENCE, Oliver: 1 item, n.d.;2 items 1948and 1990.With 2 letters from Edwin R. Clapp re. Lawrence and 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1955.
  - LELCHUK, Alan: 8 items, n.d., 1982-1990.
  - LEWIS, Janet, 1899-: 1 card, 1973,and 1 printed poem, 1972.
  - L'HEUREUX, John: 3 items, 1983-1987.With form letter to Stegner Fellows requesting material for anthology from Stanford Creative Writing Program.
  - LOMBREGLIA, Ralph: 1 item, 1992.
  - LYNCH, John A.: 6 items, 1966-1992.
  - McCORISON, Marcus A. (Marcus Allan): See Series II. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - MacDONALD, David: 1 item, 1988.
  - McGUANE, Thomas: 1 item, 1968.
  - MacINNIS, Tom: 1 item, 1966.
  - McMURRAY, George R., 1925-: 1 letter from Raymond Barry and 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1954.
  - McMURTRY, Larry: 1 item, n.d.See also Series II.
  - McPHERON, William: 2 items, 1987.
  - McWILLIAMS, Jerry, 1 item, 1975.
  - MALIN, Irving: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1956.
  - MANCINI, Pat: McNees: 2 items, 1970-1973.
  - MAYER, Tom: 21 items, 1973-1984.With newsclippings. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - MERRITT, Miriam: 3 items, 1959-1964. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - MILANI, Farzaneh: See Daneshvar, Simin. See also Series II.
  - MILLAR, Stuart: 1 item, n.d.
  - MIRRIELEES, Edith: 2 items, n.d.
  - MITCHELL, Gwen Davis: 1 item, 1966.
  - MOFFAT, Mary Jane: 3 items, n.d., 1985-1986.See also Series II.
  - MOMADAY, Natachee Scott: 6 items, 1968-1969, 1989-1991.With article about Momaday. See also Schubnell, Matthais. See also Series II.
  - MOSER, Don: 1 item, 1978.
  - MULHEIM, Harry: 2 items, 1972-1991.With article re. Mulheim.
  - NORMAN, Gurney, 1937-: 2 items, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - NORRIS, Dorothy: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1954.
  - OLIPHANT, Robert: 4 items, 1980-1983.
  - OLSEN, Tillie: 1 item, 1968.
  - PACKER, Nancy Huddleston: 2 items, 1987.With 2 letters from publisher to Stegner re. Packer. See also Series Two.
  - PAINTER, Charlotte: 6 items, 1969-1980.
  - PAPANIKOLAS, Zeese: 17 items, 1972-1992. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - PAYNE, Ladell. 1 item, 1989.
  - PEIRANO, Mary: 2 items, 1988-1991.
  - PENNYBACKER, Mindy. 1 item, 1988.
  - PFLUG, Raymond T.: 1 item, 1984. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - PHILLIPS, Rowena: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1955.
  - POPHAM, Melinda Worth: 3 items, 1989-1990.With 3 letters to Stegner from Greywolf Press re. Popham. See also Series II.
  - PRENTICE, Helen: 3 items, 1956-1991.With 2 recommendations from Stegner, 1956.
  - PUTNAM, Clay: 1 letter from Charles W. Cole re. Putnam, 1954;2 letters from Charles Marsh re. Putnam; 1 letter from John L. Clark; and recommendations from Stegner, 1954-1955.
  - RACEY, Edgar: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1956.
  - RALYER, Jerry: 1 item, 1970.
  - RANSOM, John B.: 1 item, 1989. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - RASCOE, Judith: 2 items, 1962.
  - RAWLINS, C.L. (Clem L.) [Chip]: 4 items, 1986-1992.
  - REDDEN, Dorothy: 1 item, 1965.
  - ROOD, Karen Lane: 1 item, 1987.
  - ROSENBERG, Edgar: 3 items, 1955-1968.With 3 recommendations from Stegner, 1956.
  - RYAN, Michael S.: 1 item, 1988
  - SANTOS, Bienvenido N.: 1 item, 1979.
  - SCHAEPMAN, Paul M.: 1 item, 1992.See also Series II.
  - SCHERMERHORN, James: 2 items, 1986.
  - SCHILLER, Marvin: 1 item, 1965. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - SCHRAM, Wilbur: 1 letter to Stegner re. Schram.
  - SCHUBNELL, Matthias, 1953-: 2 items, 1981-1984.
  - SCOWCROFT, Richard: 6 items and 21 recommendations by Scowcroft, 1945-1979.
  - SEGRE, Claudio G.: 2 items, 1972-1990.With copy of diary entry (1959)by Segre re. Stegner. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - SEIDENBERG, Ebe Cagli: 2 items, 1967, 1986.
  - SEWELL, [Mickey]: 2 items, 1974.
  - SHAFTON, Anthony: 2 items, 1971.
  - SHRUBB, Peter: 5 items, 1961-1971.
  - SMITH, Les (Leslie): 1 item, 1990.
  - SMITH, Tim Mason: 2 items, 1970-1974.
  - SPENCER, James: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1955.
  - SPIRO, Merrill: 27 items, 1963-1983, 1992.With newsclippings. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - STANFORD, Donald E., 1913-: 1 item, 1968. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - STARR, David: 1 item, 1992.
  - STEIN, Dona: 1 item, 1986.
  - STEELE, Tim: 1 item, n.d.
  - STEWART, Betsy Knorr: 1 item, 1965.
  - STEWART, John, 1933-: Curriculum vitae; letter of recommendation (1982)from Stegner; MacArthur Foundation letter (1982).
  - STONE, Robert: 5 items, 1966-1970.
  - STRUCINSKI, Mitchell J.: 3 items, 1960-1964.With letter from Stegner, 1960.
  - TANZER, Virginia: 2 items, 1991.With newsclipping. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - TANZER, Ward: 4 items, 1974-1983.With 1 letter to Tanzer from John Lynch.
  - TEMPLE, Eric: 1 item, 1992.
  - TERRY, Marshall: 18 items, 1970-1991.With article re. Terry. See also Series II.
  - THOMPSON, Elizabeth: 1 item, 1974. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - THOMPSON, Joanna Klassen: 2 items, 1990.
  - TODD, Richard: 2 items, 1987.
  - TOMLINSON, Norma: 1 item, 1972.
  - TUROW, Scott: 1 item, 1987.See also Series II.
  - WALKER, Dave: 1 item, 1988.
  - WATSON, Barbara: 2 items, 1946-1947.
  - WENDT, Allan: 1 item, n.d.
  - WEST, Anne: 8 items, 1972-1991.
  - WHITE, Robin: 13 items, 1965-1992.With article re. Stegner. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - WHITMORE, Stan: 1 item, 1970.
  - WILCOX, Jon: 1 item, 1992.
  - WILLIAMS, Bob: 1 item, 1966.
  - WILLIAMS, Sylvia: 4 items, 1978-1992.
  - WILLIAMSON, Barbara Tuerk: 1 item, 1990.Includes her student paper with comment by Stegner.
  - WILLIS, Mari A.: 1 item, 1974.
  - WINKES, Kenneth: 4 items, 1974, 1988, 2 n.d.
  - WINTERS, Yvor: 1 item, 1955.
  - WORTHEN, Helena: 2 items, 1986.With jacket blurb from her novel.
  - YOUNG, Al: 3 items, 1976, 1987-88.With publicity for his novel. See also Series II.
  - ZILLER, Eugene: 1 recommendation from Stegner, 1955.
  - ZOUSMER, Steve: 1 item, 1972.
  - Unidentified correspondence. Single correspondent (Neilma Gantner?) c1972-1987. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified correspondence, signatures unverified., 10 items. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous articles, publications. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series II: Literary Manuscripts, Publications, Stories.
  - ALDEN, Paulette Bates: Feeding the Eagles: Typed MS, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ALDEN, Paulette Bates: Feeding the Eagles: Typed MS, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - BERGON, Frank: Shoshone Mike: Proofs, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - BERRY, Wendell. Amplifications: Preserving Wilderness. in Wilderness, vol. 50, no. 176 (Sping 1987). How Will It Be and The Mad Farmer Revolution. In Sequoia, 1976.Issue also includes poems by Donald Davie, Venetia Gleason, N. Scott Momaday and Al Young. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - CHOWDER, Ken: Those lop-eared, whopper jawed, jack-legged Californians: Mark Twain's California. n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - DANIEL, John: Pack Rat, copy of transcript: n.d.Proof copy of Daniel's review of Stegner's publications. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - GANGEMI, Kenneth. Names. In Ploughshares, vol. 12, no. 4. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - GANTNER, Neilma: A Brief resume of the Australian Fellows at Stanford. Cassette recording. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - HALL, Donald. Argument and Persuasion. In Antaeus, no. 58 (Spring 1987).Issue also includes Jonathan Baumbach, Donald Justice and Robert Hass. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - HEINTZE, Carl: A View of the Valley. Typed MS, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - HORGAN, David: The Golden West Trio Plus One: Published edition, 1988.(Attached photo of Horgan's son) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - HOUSTON, James D.: Love Life (New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1985). (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - McCLANAHAN, Ed: Famous People I Have Known. (New York: Farrar Straus Giroux, 1985). (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - McCORISON, Marcus A.: The Bayley-Hazeb Military Road, 1959. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - McMURTRY, Larry: A Walk in Pasadena with Di-Annie and Mary Alice. In California, vol. 12, no. 3 (May, 1987). (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - MILANI, Farzani: Power, Prudence, and Print: Censorship and Simin Danashvar, 1985. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - MOFFAT, Mary Jane: City of Roses: Stories from Girlhood. (Santa Barbara: John Daniel, 1986).City of Roses: Stories from Girlhood. Photocopy of corrected galleys. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - NISBET, Jack: Sky People. Typed MS, galleys, 1984. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - PACKER, Nancy: In My Father's House. Galleys, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - PACKER, Nancy: The Women who Walk and other stories. Typed MS, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - POPHAM, Melinda Worth: Skywalker: Typed MS, n.d.(pp. 1-126). (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - POPHAM, Melinda Worth: Skywalker: Typed MS, n.d.:(pp. 127-257). (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - SCHAEPMAN, Paul: Phaedra and Cassandra, La Balada De Salteador de Comidos, Swala Tomi. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - TERRY, Marshall: Ringer: Typed MS, with corrections, 1986. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - TUROW, Scott. Presumed Innocent. Typed MS, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - WEAVER, Will. Red Earth, White Earth. (New York: Simon and Schuster, 1986). (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Grassroots Development, vol. 9, no. 2 (1985). (Box 6, Folder 5)